

Senior Android Developer

\$ Expected Salary: +10.000.000 T 

★ Military Service: Is-Finishing

Phone: +98-9194090212 in LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/aminography

Email: aminography@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/aminography

I'm a creative and lead Android Developer with approximately 8 YEARS of experience in programming Android apps/libs for mobile devices in the field of messengers, e-commerce, tourism, *etc*. I'm always eager to keep my knowledge updated and learn new technologies in order to improve my career.

# Working Experiences

• Jan 2018 – Jun 2019 Lead Android Developer

Moj Secure E-Commerce, Tehran, Iran

• Sep 2015 – Jan 2018 Research Assistant

Social Data Science Lab, Department of Computer Engineering and Information Technology, Amirkabir University of Technology - Tehran Polytechnic, Tehran, Iran

• Dec 2015 - Mar 2017 Lead Android Developer & UI/UX Designer

Soroush Media Technology Development, Tehran, Iran

• Jun 2012 – Oct 2016 Android & Java Developer

Mohaymen ICT, Tehran, Iran

# Education

• M.Sc. in Computer Engineering (Software Engineering), Amirkabir University of Technology - Tehran Polytechnic, Tehran, Iran (2018)

GPA: 3.91 / 4.00

Thesis: Providing a method for detecting communities in complex networks

• B.Sc. in Computer Engineering (Software Engineering), K. N. Toosi University of Technology, Tehran, Iran (2015)

GPA: 3.46 / 4.00

Thesis: Design and implementation of a remote control system by using android smartphones

# Skills

## • Programming Languages Proficiency

Expert: Java, Kotlin

Intermediate: Python, C/C++ (Android NDK)

Novice: R, PHP, VHDL, Prolog

#### • Version Control Systems

Git, SVN

#### • Build Tools

Gradle, Maven, Ant

#### • Database Systems

SQLite, MySQL

#### • Special Topics

- Object Oriented Principals, Software Architecture, Design Patterns, Performance Optimization
- Multi-Threading, Socket Programming, Annotation Processing
- Cryptography, Network Security, VOIP

#### • Research Interests

- Network Science, Graph Theory
- Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing
- Algorithms

#### • Languages

Persian: Native
English: Fluent
Arabic: Elementary

# Some Notable Projects (Ordered by Time)

## • VAS-SDK [Moj Secure E-Commerce]

*VAS-SDK* is a tool developed in order to organize telecommunication operator third-party services. The main problem for this area is undesirable pay for unwanted subscriptions. I, as the chief developer of this project, have designed an *SDK* to regulate the huge amount of money that flows on the entire system. *MCI* (*Hamrah-e-aval*) who is known as the first and the most developed telecommunication operator in Iran, is the main employer of this project. All VAS-based businesses are obliged to use our product, which will publish soon.

# • Ostad Motahari [Moj Secure E-Commerce]

Ostad Motahari application has been developed for Shahid Motahari Scientific and Cultural Foundation in order to publish his books and lectures. Based on these contents, it includes contests, training courses, and licencing. This app has +1k active installs on GooglePlay and +2ok on CafeBazaar (i.e. the largest Iranian application market). It is fully developed using Kotlin language.

# • Toodid [Moj Secure E-Commerce]

*Toodid* is a content based application and its purpose is to publish useful contents in the field of fashion and clothing. It is fully developed using *Kotlin* language.

## • Rezvan [Moj Secure E-Commerce]

*Rezvan* is an application for guiding pilgrims with more than 1 million active installs (*based on registered mobile numbers*). It enables users to create group of fellows in order to communicate and share their location on map. It is also possible to watch live broadcast videos from religious sites in addition to many other features.

# • Soroush Messenger [Mohaymen ICT | Soroush Media Technology Development]

*Soroush Messenger* is the most popular Iranian instant messenger with more than 100k *GooglePlay* active installs and +1 million on *CafeBazaar*.

# • Sayna Messenger [Mohaymen ICT]

The main purpose of *Sayna Messenger* is its roaming ability, which provides an infrastructure for users to make international phone calls through the internet. It is also possible to make a call with landline phone numbers. It was developed for the largest mobile telecommunication company in Iran, *MCI*.

## • Secure Bulletin [Mohaymen ICT]

*Secure Bulletin* is a news feeding application that delivers the news through a secure channel using asymmetric cryptography. It is also possible that each news carry multiple attachment files.

## • Kelk Calendar [Mohaymen ICT]

*Kelk Calendar* is an Android calendar which supports Persian, Gregorian, and Hijri dates at the same time. It is the first Android application that I developed.

# Some Personal Projects

# • PrimeDatePicker [Available on Github]

The lack of a good library for picking date which was compatible with Persian dates led to the development of *PrimeDatePicker*. *PrimeDatePicker* is a tool which provides the functionality of picking a single day as well as a range of days for Persian, Hijri, Japanese, and Gregorian calendars. Its internal elements such as *MonthView* and *CalendarView* are stand-alone components that can be used separately also. These components are flexible and fully customizable.

#### • PrimeCalendar [Available on Github]

*PrimeCalendar* provides all the *java.util.Calendar* functionalities for Persian, Hijri, Japanese, and common Gregorian dates. Furthermore, *PrimeCalendar* supplies conversion between the mentioned dates. This library can be used in every JVM-based projects such as Java/Kotlin applications, Android apps, *etc*.

# • ChoosePhotoHelper [Available on Github]

Picking an image as an avatar in Android apps needs to write a bunch of error-prone boilerplate codes. *ChoosePhotoHelper* develops a component which facilitates picking photos from gallery or taking an image with the camera without any boilerplate codes. It also internally handles some issues like rotation correction of the taken photos, permission request for camera and gallery (if needed), *URI* exposure problem, *etc*.

# • PrimeAdapter [Available on Github]

Writing an extensible code to show lists and grids using *RecyclerView* is a challenging task for many Android developers. *PrimeAdapter* tackles this challenge by separating the required code in a few simple and well-structured classes. Moreover, it brings simplicity when there are multiple view types. Therefore, the developer can handle them in a reusable and extensible structure.

## • RedirectGlide [Available on Github]

One of the issues with image *URLs*, is that sometimes the real *URL* of an image is beyond a webservice api or there is an indirect/shortened link to it. *Glide*, which is one of the most powerful tools to cache and show images in Android, does not handle the mentioned issue. Therefore, *RedirectGlide* enables *Glide* to efficiently load such images according to *Glide*'s framework.

Last updated: October 31, 2019